hello there welcome to the keynote our
您好，欢迎来到我们的主题演讲
laziness the ultimate sophistication
懒惰终极复杂
both in life and programming my name is
无论是生活还是编程，我的名字是
Becca Subramanyam I'm gonna talk about
我要谈谈Becca Subramanyam
my excitement around functional style of
我对函数式风格的兴奋
programming how practical is it to
编程对它有多实用
really achieve that and how language is
真正做到这一点，以及语言如何
like Java make it really easy for us
像Java这样对我们来说真的很容易
well we've been programming in the
好吧，我们一直在
imperative style most of the predominant
命令式风格最主要
mainstream languages provide impetus
主流语言提供动力
Tylar programming for a very long time
Tylar编程很长时间
well in the impetus trail of programming
很好地推动了编程
we focus on what to do but unfortunately
我们专注于做什么，但不幸的是
mostly on how to do let's talk about
主要是关于怎么做，让我们来谈谈
this with a really small little example
这有一个很小的例子
a trivial example but nevertheless place
一个琐碎的例子，但仍然存在
with illustrates the point really well
很好地说明了这一点
so let's get started with a little
所以让我们开始一点
example here here's a list of names half
例子这里是一个名字列表
of which we cannot see but I'm curious
其中我们看不到，但我很好奇
either a friend Nemo in the list how do
清单中的朋友Nemo怎么办
we solve this problem well an imperative
我们必须很好地解决这个问题
style it starts with a ceremony right
风格以仪式开始
off the bat so first of all say boolean
脱颖而出，所以首先说布尔
thousand is equal to in this case false
在这种情况下，千等于false
we want to then say for pick one name at
然后我们想说要在
a time from the list of course and then
从清单中选择一个时间，然后
we gonna examine given each of the name
我们将检查给出的每个名称
we're gonna ask you that name is equal
我们要问你名字相等
to well of course the word Nemo well if
当然很好的话Nemo这个词，如果
it is found we declare the victory by
发现我们宣告胜利
setting found equal to true but not so
发现设置等于true但不是这样
fast you better remember to break out of
快，你最好记得突围
this as well otherwise we'll be cut into
这也一样，否则我们将被切成
process even after we found the result
即使找到结果也要处理
which is not very good for performance
这对性能不是很好
especially when we have a very large
特别是当我们有一个很大的
collection but not quite done yet we
收集但尚未完成
still have to come back and examine the
仍然必须回来检查
found and then we have to say output
找到，然后我们必须说输出
Nemo found and celebrate about it of
Nemo发现并为此庆祝
course sadly we couldn't find Nemo will
当然可惜我们找不到尼莫
then declare saying oh maybe that Nemo
然后宣布说哦，也许那尼莫
was not found quite here in this case so
在这种情况下在这里找不到
we'll say Nemo not found maybe play sad
我们会说找不到Nemo可能会伤心
music let's go ahead and run this code
音乐，让我们继续运行此代码
and see yay good news we found Nemo
看到好消息，我们发现了尼莫
that's imperative style of programming
这是势在必行的编程风格
well I call this accidental complexity
好吧，我称之为偶然的复杂性
because in the imperative style we focus
因为在命令式风格中我们专注于
on what to do but also on how to do it
在做什么上，也在如何做上
we could drag into the details of how we
我们可以将详细信息拖入
had to take every single element we have
必须考虑我们拥有的每个要素
to compare the
比较
element we have to set a flag and don't
元素，我们必须设置一个标志，不要
remember to break out of the loop every
记得每次都要打破循环
single piece is your responsibility our
单件是您的责任，我们
responsibility when it comes to coding
编码方面的责任
in the style of programming so introduce
以编程风格介绍
style of programming is where we get
编程风格是我们的目标
pumped down with the details that
抽出的细节
introduces accidental complexity makes
引入意外的复杂性
code really hard to change that's the
代码真的很难改变
past
过去
every single mainstream language did
每一种主流语言都做到了
this to us but it's not our fault as
这对我们来说，但这不是我们的错
programmers but we had to really work
程序员，但我们必须真正工作
with tools given to us and what's mostly
提供给我们的工具，主要是
available and popular as well but the
可用和受欢迎，但
good news is the future is moving in a
好消息是未来正在前进
different direction almost every new
几乎每个新的方向都不同
mainstream language today is moving
今天的主流语言在移动
towards the functional style of
朝着
programming well the future isn't
做好编程，未来不是
decorated style and function of style
声明式风格和函数式风格
let's talk about technologies file first
让我们先谈谈技术文件
going back to this example this was a
回到这个例子，这是一个
lot of ceremony a lot of noise to find
大量的仪式找到很多噪音
Nemo let's get rid of all the noise and
Nemo让我们摆脱所有的噪音和
ceremony in this code right here and I
这段代码中的仪式
will just come down to the found right
只会归结为发现的权利
here and change it to let's say name
在这里并将其更改为假设名称
start contains and then of course ask
开始包含，然后当然问
for Nemo what all that effort we had to
对于Nemo，我们要做的所有努力
put in is gone we can quickly come here
放进去了，我们可以很快来这里
and get the result that's an example of
得到的结果就是一个例子
decorative style of programming so what
声明式风格的程序设计怎么样
is a decorative style salt in the Tecla
是Tecla中的声明式风格盐
relative style we can focus on what to
相对风格，我们可以专注于
do and not on how to do it so we focus
而不是如何去做，所以我们专注
on what to do that is our main focus
关于该做什么是我们的主要重点
whatever we interested in so focus on
无论我们感兴趣的是什么
what to do not on how to do it well the
怎么做就不好做
decorative style removes all the
声明式风格消除了所有
accidental complicity in the code we
代码中的意外共谋
might ask the question how does
可能会问这个问题
containers really do the work
容器确实可以完成工作
what answer possibly is it's doing
答案可能是什么
exactly this we come up with all other
正是这一点，我们提出了所有其他建议
kinds of ideas as to how contains works
关于如何包含作品的各种想法
and different languages may implement
并且可能会使用不同的语言
contains differently but I like a better
包含不同但我喜欢更好
answer and that is I don't care okay
回答，那是我不在乎
maybe that's a little rude but rather
也许有点不礼貌，但是
than saying I don't care we can say it's
比说我不在乎我们可以说
encapsulated well that sounds so much
封装得好，听起来好多
better well meaning
更好的含义
I don't care well true we can all agree
我不在乎，我们都可以同意
that there are times we absolutely care
有时候我们绝对在乎
but the beauty with the Declaration of
但宣言的美丽
programming is we can get to the details
编程是我们可以得到的细节
when we care about it we don't care
当我们关心它时，我们不在乎
about it it's not on our face in the
关于它，它不在我们的脸上
imperative style we have no choice
势在必行的风格我们别无选择
whatsoever the details are in front of
任何细节都摆在面前
us whether we like it or not we have
我们，不管我们喜欢与否
absolutely no escape from the details so
绝对无法逃避细节，所以
in the decorative style we focus on what
在声明式风格上，我们专注于
to do not on how to do it well that's
不要去做得很好
decorated so think decorative leave
装饰，所以认为装饰假
first functional comes next in
第一个功能进来
functional style of programming we are
我们编程的函数式风格
also using decorative style functional
还使用声明式风格功能
style programming is not new thank
样式编程不是新的谢谢
goodness it's not new it's not a
天哪，这不是新的，不是
newfangled idea invented last night it's
昨晚发明的新想法
been around for a very long time
已经存在很长时间了
it's been tried it tested and been
经过尝试，经过测试，
practiced quite a bit it just was not
练习了很多，只是没有
popular in the mainstream languages but
在主流语言中很流行，但是
almost all mainstream languages now are
现在几乎所有主流语言都是
providing functional style of
提供函数式风格
programming which is really phenomenal
编程真的很棒
so this is a very old idea but with
所以这是一个非常古老的想法
renewed interest what are some of the
重新产生的兴趣是什么
reasons for it well the world we live in
我们生活的世界之所以很好
has changed quite a bit the type of
已经改变了很多类型
applications we develop the type of data
应用我们开发的数据类型
we process and deal with a lot of these
我们处理并处理了很多这些
things are different from applications
情况与应用不同
we develop 20-30 years ago but what is
我们发展20-30年前，但是
the charm of functional style of
函数式风格的魅力
programming let's talk about that right
编程让我们谈谈这个权利
here for that let's take slightly
为此，让我们稍微
different example here than the names
与名称不同的示例
let's start with a list of numbers let's
让我们从数字列表开始
say one to ten given these numbers I'll
给这些数字说一到十
say finally total of the double of even
说最后总的偶数
numbers well great I want to find the
数字很​​好，我想找到
title of double of even numbers well
偶数双精度标题
what's the imperative style do it beats
它击败的命令式风格是什么
you down from the beginning isn't it
你从一开始就失望了，不是吗
result is equal to zero for integer
结果等于零（整数）
element coming from the numbers
来自数字的元素
collection we then say if element Mar 2
然后我们说元素3月2日的集合
is equal to 0 then of course we'll say
等于0那么我们当然会说
result plus equal to and then e times 2
结果加等于，然后e乘以2
and when we are done with this whole
当我们完成这一切时
thing we can display the output of the
我们可以显示的输出
result right here in the very end so we
结果就在最后，所以我们
can see the result is 60
可以看到结果是60
that's quite a bit of work again an
再次需要大量的工作
imperative style of programming we will
势在必行的编程风格
switch here to a rather a functional
在这里切换到相当实用的功能
style of programming or what in the
编程风格或
world is functional style not all
世界是函数式风格，并非全部
declarative code declarative code is
声明代码声明代码是
functional remember the contains method
功能记住contains方法
that contains method is declarative but
包含方法是声明性的，但
not functional but all functional code
不是功能，而是所有功能代码
is declarative so this is declarative
是声明性的，所以这是声明性的
plus higher order functions so what in
再加上高阶函数，那么
the world is higher order functions what
世界是高阶函数
decorated is where we say what to do and
装饰是我们说要做什么的地方，
not how to do it let's go to that being
不是怎么做，让我们去
real quick and see the example so it
很快，请看示例
started with an output right off the bat
一开始就从输出开始
number start stream per stream is a
每个流的起始流数是
fancy internal iterator what's on a
花哨的内部迭代器是什么
filter given an element element ma du is
给定元素element ma du的过滤器
equal to 0 so we get only even values
等于0，所以我们只得到偶数值
from the collection then we perform a
从集合中，然后我们执行
map to let's say double right here and
映射到这里说双重
then in this case our map to intruder
然后在这种情况下我们的入侵者地图
map to end and we will go ahead and
计划结束，我们将继续前进，
double the element times two and once we
将元素加倍两次，然后我们
of course double the value will call the
当然，将值加倍会调用
sum off it and get the total of the
总结一下，得到的总数
double of the even values when we run
运行时偶数的两倍
the code notice the result is still the
代码注意结果仍然是
same in this code example it is
在此代码示例中相同
decorated because we told what to do
装饰，因为我们告诉该怎么办
grandpa from the some operating perform
爷爷从一些手术表演
filter perform mapping or transformation
过滤器执行映射或转换
of the data but it's high in order
数据，但顺序较高
because we are passing a function to
因为我们要传递一个函数给
another function the highlighted code of
另一个功能突出显示的代码
course is a lambda expression and
当然是lambda表达式，
expressions are lambdas or anonymous
表达式是lambda或匿名
functions we're passing a function to
函数，我们将一个函数传递给
this filter method or filter function so
这种过滤方法或过滤功能
in higher order functions we can pass
在更高阶的函数中，我们可以通过
functions around we can pass a function
我们周围的功能可以传递一个功能
to a function create a function with our
用我们的函数创建函数
function even return a function from a
函数甚至从
function those make in higher order so
那些使更高阶的功能
this line of code is functional meaning
这行代码是功能性含义
it is declared a plus higher order on
它被宣布为
the other hand similarly this one is
另一方面，这是
functional as well but this one is
以及功能，但这一是
purely declarative so this of course is
纯粹是声明性的，所以这当然是
focused on telling what to do we're not
专注于告诉我们该怎么做
passing any functions to these functions
将任何功能传递给这些功能
and
和
basically the functional style of
基本上是函数式风格
programming but what's the charm of a
编程，但是一个程序的魅力是什么
functional style of programming the
编程的函数式风格
charm of functional programming is
函数式编程的魅力是
highly expressive code so the code
高表现力的代码，所以代码
becomes a lot more easier to work with
变得更容易使用
easier to write let's look at one
更容易写让我们看一个
example of this to see how beautifully
这个例子看看有多漂亮
the code begins to flow I was teaching
我开始教的代码开始流行
the Java eight cores for a client and
Java客户端的八个核心
they have been using Java 8 already and
他们已经在使用Java 8了，
what if the developer said can you take
如果开发人员说您可以接受该怎么办
a look at our code and critique it
看看我们的代码并对其进行批判
usually I get scared when people ask
通常当人们问我时我会害怕
this question what if the code is really
这个问题，如果代码真的是
highly complex and I cannot understand
非常复杂，我听不懂
it I don't want to insult them by saying
我不想通过说来侮辱他们
anything well in this case the code was
在这种情况下代码很好
written using Java 8 streams I just
我只是用Java 8流编写的
started reading the code and even I who
开始阅读代码，甚至我谁
doesn't have any understanding of their
对他们没有任何了解
domain was able to quickly understand
域能够快速了解
what they were doing that's one of the
他们正在做的事情就是其中之一
biggest charms of functional style of
函数式风格的最大魅力
programming let's start with a create
编程让我们从创建开始
people list right here and given a list
人们在这里列出并给出列表
of people let's say I want to go ahead
有人说我想继续前进
and store that here into list let's say
并将其存储在列表中
person people is equal to create people
人等于创造人
but I want to find the names let's say
但我想找个名字
get the names all in uppercase let's say
让名字全部大写
and then of course of everyone who is
当然，每个人
younger than 18 oh that should be easy
不到18岁哦，应该很容易
isn't get the names in all in uppercase
不是全部用大写字母
of everyone younger than 18 well we
每个18岁以下的人
could start again with the list string
可以从列表字符串重新开始
over here so we could say string and we
在这里，所以我们可以说字符串，我们
could say juniors just to call them as
可以说大三生只是称呼他们为
juniors or kids if you want to call them
大三或小孩，如果你想打电话给他们
kids though 17 year old may really
虽然17岁的孩子可能真的
object to it but let's call it as kids
反对它，但让我们称之为孩子
is equal to new arrays and in this case
等于新数组，在这种情况下
ArrayList and we create an empty list
ArrayList，我们创建一个空列表
look at the ceremony again we're
再看一次仪式，我们
spending time telling how to do things
花时间告诉他们如何做事
and then far a person and given a person
然后一个人又给一个人
coming from the people collection and
来自人们的收藏
what are we going to do with every
我们将与每个人做什么
single person we say if the person d'art
我们说单身的人
get age is greater than well less than
年龄大于小于
18 then of course we're going to say a
18然后我们当然要说一个
kid start and well then of course get
孩子开始，然后当然得到
the name of the person get name and then
该人的名字得到名字，然后
to uppercase
大写
and then of course added to the kids
然后当然添加到孩子们
collection when they're done with that
完成后收集
we'll go ahead and I don't put the
我们会继续，我不把
values for kids and quickly glancing at
孩子们的价值观并迅速浏览
this we see that there is Jack Jack what
这我们看到有杰克杰克
are the Jack's and Jill who are less
杰克和吉尔少一些
than 18 let's see if the court produces
超过18岁，让我们看看法院是否产生
that result and sure enough it's Jack
结果肯定是杰克
and Jill but if you look at this code
和吉尔，但如果您看这段代码
there is a few different there are few
有一些不同，有一些
different problems in this code it's
这段代码中的不同问题是
verbose to begin with
冗长的开头
second it lacks cohesion what in the
其次，它缺乏凝聚力
world am I talking about well look at
我正在谈论的世界好看
this one line of code it's doing one too
这一行代码也正在做一件事
many things it had to get the name it
它得名的许多事情
actor turns for me to uppercase it had
演员把我变成大写
to Hat to the collection that's a lot of
到帽子到很多
work and of course that somebody comes
工作，当然有人来
along and says it's a very long list
并说这是一个很长的清单
make it parallel you're gonna find the
使它平行，您将找到
nearest exit to get out a lot of work to
最近的出口要去做很多工作
make this chord parallel of course but
当然让这个和弦平行
we can save a lot of effort by going
我们可以通过以下方式节省很多精力
functional on this that's the charm of
在这方面的功能是
functional the style so what is the
功能的风格是什么
charm in this example we can now again
在这个例子中，我们现在可以再次魅力
start once once more output but this
再一次开始输出，但这
time we would start with people
我们从人开始的时间
collection I don't look at the stream
收藏我不看流
again
再次
we'll do a filter given a person will
给定一个人的意愿，我们将进行过滤
simply say person dot get age is less
只是说人点年龄变小
than 18 but then we'll perform a map
超过18，但我们将执行地图
would say given a person give me the
会说给定一个人给我
person dot get name right here or as we
人点在这里或我们的名字
would do with refactor this to using
可以将其重构为使用
method references in just a minute we
只需一分钟，方法引用
can then say given a name we'll say name
然后可以说出名字，我们将说出名字
to uppercase right here and then once we
在这里大写，然后一旦我们
get the upper case we can say collect
得到大写，我们可以说收集
and we will collect it into a nice
我们将其收集到一个漂亮的
little list if you will so here is to
小清单，如果您愿意，这里是
list and of course to list comes from
列表，当然列表来自
the collectors of utility method so
实用方法的收集者
we'll say collectors and right there is
我们说收藏家，就在那里
the to list coming from the collectors
来自收藏家的清单
let's go ahead and run this code and see
让我们继续运行此代码，看看
what it does and of course in this case
它做什么，当然在这种情况下
given a person I should spell it
给一个人我应该拼写
properly here is a person and of course
合适的是一个人，当然
go ahead and run this code and see
继续运行此代码，看看
that's a jack-and-jill but look at the
那是杰克和吉尔，但看看
function composition we see right here
我们在这里看到的功能组合
give it a collection of person
给它一个人的集合
we get all the people in more than 18
我们让所有人都超过了18岁
get their name convert to uppercase and
得到他们的名字转换为大写和
put it back into a list it becomes a one
把它放回一个清单就变成一个
flow to top to bottom we don't have to
从上到下流，我们不必
go back and forth to understand there is
来回去了解那里
no need for the breaks and continues and
无需休息并继续
all that thing we do it becomes a lot
我们做的所有事情变得很多
easier of course we could take this one
当然，我们可以轻松一点
and say string colon colon and use a
并说字符串冒号冒号，并使用
method reference as well and likewise we
方法参考，同样，我们
could use a method reference here do so
可以在这里使用方法参考
we can save quite a bit of effort and
我们可以节省很多精力，
reading this code and make it really
阅读这段代码并使之真正成为现实
elegant if you want so in this case of
优雅，如果您想在这种情况下
course given a person we are going to
当然给了我们要去的人
get the person's name and then we're
得到这个人的名字，然后我们
going to convert it to uppercase and get
将其转换为大写并得到
the result this function composition is
该函数组成的结果是
extremely compelling and so that's one
非常引人注目，所以这是一个
of the biggest benefits we can out of
我们最大的好处
this but of course the question is
这当然是问题
what's the catch
有什么收获
that's what intelligent programmers
那就是聪明的程序员
always ask what's the catch well let's
总是问有什么收获，让我们
talk about the big elephant in the room
谈论房间里的大象
I've never walked into a client site
我从未走进客户网站
where the minute I talk about Java 8 and
我谈论Java 8的那一刻
functional programming the immediate
立即进行功能编程
question is gosh but what about
问题是天哪，那又怎么样
performance performance is something
性能表现
extremely important but it turns out not
非常重要，但事实并非如此
all languages are created equal
所有语言都是平等的
let's just take a detour and take a look
让我们绕道看看
at Ruby real quick before I get started
在开始之前，很快就在Ruby上学习
though on this I want to emphasize one
尽管在此我想强调一个
thing I love Ruby I don't want me saying
我爱露比的事我不想我说
negative things about a language to be
关于一种语言的消极事物
taken as a hateful comment I'm I'm
被视为仇恨言论，我是
objective I want to show good things and
我想要展示美好的事物，
I want to show not-so-good things as
我想展示不太好的东西
well in fact I would even point that
其实我什至会指出
about Java 8 in the end I love Ruby I
关于Java 8到底我爱Ruby I
use Ruby extensively our god
广泛使用Ruby我们的上帝
applications I maintain in production
我在生产中维护的应用程序
using Ruby as well as much as a lot of
使用Ruby以及很多
other languages however from the
但是其他语言
language point of view I looked like to
我想要的语言观点
learn from what the strengths and
从长处学习
weaknesses of languages are the
语言的弱点是
strengths of Ruby is pure elegance it's
Ruby的优点是纯粹的优雅
beautiful
美丽
no ceremony so it's a really good
没有仪式，所以真的很好
language for a certain type of things we
某种事物的语言
do kind of like a bicycle versus serve
做得像单车还是发球
rocket if you want to think about it
火箭，如果你想考虑一下
that way there are planes when
这样有飞机的时候
rocket is maybe the right vehicle to use
火箭也许是使用的正确工具
a lot of times bicycle is awesome to use
很多时候自行车很棒
and I want to be able to pick and choose
我希望能够选择
what may make sense let's talk about
什么可能有意义，让我们来谈谈
Ruby real quick so here I'm in the Ruby
Ruby非常快，所以我在Ruby中
source code let's talk about a little
源代码让我们谈一点
transformation I want to do let's do
我想做的转变让我们做
numbers is equal to and I want to save
数字等于，我要保存
one two three maybe a few numbers right
一二三也许是几个数字
here I don't want to take these numbers
在这里我不想取这些数字
but what do I want to do I'm gonna say
但是我要说的是什么
find the first let's say what find E
找到第一个，说说找到E
let's say double off are all even
比方说双倍都
numbers so I want to find the double of
数字，所以我想找到
all even numbers well that shouldn't be
所有偶数都不应该是
really hard to do is it well if I want
如果我想真的很难做
to find the double of all even numbers
找出所有偶数的双数
I'm gonna just take every number fine
我要把每个数字都罚款
which is even double it and then of
甚至是它的两倍
course you know total it well okay
当然，你知道这一切还好吧
that's not really that hard but to
其实并不难，但要
change the problem a little bit what if
稍微改变问题，如果
this collection we're to have our
这个集合，我们要有我们的
different values along the way say maybe
一路上的不同价值观也许
some things along these lines I'm gonna
我会遵循这些思路
change it to some arbitrary values that
将其更改为一些任意值
I'm going to work with so in this
我将为此工作
example of course I've got a bunch of
我当然有很多
different values but find that let's say
不同的值，但发现
find thee a double let's say double and
找到你一个双重的，让我们说双重和
off the first number a greater than o
偏离第一个数字大于o
let's say in this case greater than what
让我们说在这种情况下大于
of 50 so I want to find the double of
的50，所以我想找到
the first number greater than 50 so how
第一个大于50的数字
would I do this well we are like
我会做得好吗，我们就像
function of style of programming it's
编程风格的功能是
charming it's beautiful its elegant how
迷人，美丽，优雅
easy it is to understand the code and
很容易理解代码
Ruby has been supporting the functional
Ruby一直支持该功能
side of programming as much as
编程方面
imperative style of programming from day
从今天起势在必行的编程风格
one so in that sense Ruby is beings been
因此，从这个意义上讲，Ruby是
doing what Java has been recently doing
做Java最近做的事情
providing both imperative and functional
提供命令性和功能性
style of programming well let's give it
好的编程风格，让我们给它
a try so numbers dart map just like how
试试看，数字飞镖地图就像
we used a map function right here for
我们在这里使用了地图功能
transforming we could use a map function
转换我们可以使用地图功能
oh but wait a minute we want numbers
哦，等等，我们要数字
greater than 50 isn't it so we could say
大于50是不是所以我们可以说
we could say filter
我们可以说过滤器
and give an element over here so here is
并在此处给出一个元素，所以这里是
an element this is Ruby syntax we could
这是我们可以使用的Ruby语法的元素
say a greater than will say is greater
说更大比说更大
than well is greater than in in this
比这还好
case 50 and we're going to ask if it's
案例50，我们要问是否
greater than 50 for this particular
大于50
element so we'll go ahead and write that
元素，所以我们继续写
function e is greater than 50 given a
给定a，函数e大于50
number n I want to simply return this
我想简单地返回这个
value will say return n is greater than
值将表示return n大于
how charming that's great then we'd say
那太好了，然后我们会说
a map function in this case of course
当然在这种情况下的地图功能
given an element we will say we want to
给定一个元素，我们会说我们想要
double the element so we'll double the
加倍元素，所以我们加倍
element right off the back so this
元素就在后面，所以这
requires us to write a double function
需要我们写一个双重函数
which takes a number n and all that it's
这需要一个数字n和所有的
going to do is return n times 2 that's
要做的是返回n倍2
awesome so far but remember all I don't
到目前为止很棒，但请记住我所没有的
I don't want all of the values I want
我不想要所有的价值观
just the first value and we will of
只是第一个值，我们将
course print this result when we are
当然，当我们
done right here so let's say puts and
就在这里完成，所以我们说看跌期权和
ask it to print the result so let's go
要求它打印结果，让我们开始吧
ahead and try this my number 13 has an
继续尝试，我的13号有一个
error we'll fix it so in this case
错误，我们将对此进行修复
numbers in this case of course we gonna
在这种情况下，数字我们当然会
say find are all we're gonna ask for
说找到就是我们要的全部
every single value and then double it
每个值，然后将其加倍
well find out is equal into our filter
找出等于等于进入我们的过滤器
right here in Ruby well the first number
就在Ruby中，第一个数字
that's greater than 50 is 54 so the
大于50是54，所以
times 2 is 108 we can see that so that's
2是108，我们可以看到
doing the work but remember in this
做工作，但要记住
example we really wanted the first value
例子，我们真的想要第一个值
that meet just meets the criteria but
满足只是符合条件，但
how much work did Ruby really do in this
Ruby在这方面实际上做了多少工作
particular case well it turns out ruby
很好的案例证明是红宝石
was very eager it did a lot of work so
非常渴望它做了很多工作，所以
if you go over here and print if you
如果你去这里打印，如果你
will in this case we'll say e is greater
在这种情况下，我们会说e更大
than and then we'll print the value that
比，然后我们将输出
we are asking for and then we'll go to
我们要的，然后我们去
the double and then ask it to print the
双，然后要求它打印
result of double and then of course
当然是两倍的结果
specify what the value is
指定值是什么
notice all the processing we did we
注意我们所做的所有处理
computed we checked if every single
计算我们检查是否每一个
value is greater than 50 all the way
一路大于50
from the one to the end 20 then we
从一个到最后20
doubled all the values greater than 50
将所有大于50的值加倍
54 61 77 98 and finally we discarded
54 61 77 98，最后我们丢弃了
everything and just get the first value
一切，只是获得第一价值
what a waste of performance nothing is
浪费性能什么都没有
great for what it does but what if I'm
伟大的事，但如果我是
dealing with a large amount of data in
处理大量数据
some projects I'm working with we are
我正在合作的一些项目
dealing with literally millions and
处理数以百万计的
millions of data this would not work
数百万个数据将无法正常工作
really well in such situations isn't it
在这种情况下真的很好，不是吗
so what really attracted me to Java 8 is
所以真正吸引我使用Java 8的是
not the fact that it actually has the
不是事实，它实际上有
function of style of programming in all
全部编程风格的功能
honesty I kind of discarded what Java it
诚实我有点舍弃了Java
provided to begin with because I said
提供开始，因为我说
what's the big deal other languages have
其他语言有什么大不了的
lambdas Java now has lambdas why should
lambdas Java现在有lambdas为什么
I care but I found there's a lot more
我在乎，但我发现还有更多
than lambdas in Java 8 and that's what
比Java 8中的lambda更重要
really drew me towards Java 8 elegance
确实使我着迷于Java 8的优雅
is very useful we would not discard them
非常有用，我们不会丢弃它们
beautiful code is great code that is
漂亮的代码就是很棒的代码
expressive code that is easier to
易于表达的代码
communicate with awesome that's great
与很棒的人交流
but performance is critical give me four
但是性能很关键，请给我四个
famines or give me death is probably a
饥荒或给我死亡可能是一个
slogan we can all say so elegance in the
口号，我们都可以说得如此优雅
admins of performance is not gonna scale
表现的管理员不会扩大规模
really well so what gives what we do are
真的很好，所以我们能做的是
we doomed with this kind of programming
我们注定要这种编程
then where we can have either
然后我们可以在其中
performance or we can have elegance but
性能或我们可以有优雅，但
not both well it turns out that's not
两者都不好，事实证明那不是
entirely true
完全正确
let's look at other languages to learn
让我们看看其他语言来学习
from let's turn to a truly functional
从我们转向真正的功能
programming language Haskell I really
编程语言Haskell我真的
love Haskell for what it does let's take
爱Haskell所做的事让我们接受
a look at Haskell really quickly if you
如果您很快就能快速了解Haskell
look at Haskell right here I'm gonna
看看Haskell就在这里
write a method call a function called
写一个方法调用一个函数
add a B equals a plus B so in this case
加B等于加B因此在这种情况下
it's gonna return the result total of a
它会返回结果的总数
plus B but these functions and hostel
加B但这些功能和旅馆
are known as pure functions now we write
现在被称为纯函数
an evaluate function when it takes a
需要一个
value and returns a value and of course
值并返回值，当然
I'm gonna write a main function which
我要写一个主要功能
has a side-effect
有副作用
I put an equal right there and then I'm
我在那放平等的权利，然后
gonna say rent and the print is going to
要说租金和印刷品
print evaluate let's go to print add one
打印评估，让我们去打印添加一个
and three what I run this of course it
和三个我当然会运行它
says four however in this example I have
说四个，但是在这个例子中我有
still had to do all the work
仍然必须做所有的工作
unlike a lot of other languages applies
与许多其他语言不同
what is called by normal order while a
正常命令所称的是
lot of of other languages are languages
许多其他语言是语言
including Java use what is called
包括Java使用所谓的
applicative order so what in the world
应用顺序，这到底是什么
is the difference between those two
两者之间的区别是什么
normal order is quite abnormal as you
你的正常秩序很不正常
can see not a lot of languages do this
看不出很多语言能做到这一点
is the evaluation of the function is
是功能的评估是
postponed untilled the value of that
推迟到那个值
evaluation is actually needed in this
对此实际上需要评估
example ad is not going to be called
示例广告将不会被调用
until we step in to evaluate so if ad is
直到我们介入评估，以便确定广告是否
not needed at all it would never get
根本不需要它永远不会得到
executed let's prove this in this case
在这种情况下，让我们证明一下
I'm gonna show that ad is going to be
我要展示的是广告将会
actually called well I can't put a print
真的打得好，我不能打印
statement in there because prints are
那里的声明，因为打印
side effects so what are we gonna do
副作用，我们该怎么办
here well the way we'll work through
在这里，我们将通过的方式
this is to bring up the GHC I the
这是为了提起GHC I
compiler and I'm gonna load up the
编译器，我要加载
Haskell file into it I'm gonna put a
Haskell文件放进去，我要放一个
breakpoint on line number one character
第一行字符上的断点
16 and I'm gonna ask me to be evaluated
16我要请我接受评估
notice it stopped on line number 1 when
注意它在第1行停止
I say continue now you can see it
我说现在继续可以看到它
produce the result of 4 so I just proved
产生4的结果，所以我证明了
that it executed the add function ignore
它执行添加功能忽略
that we'll come back to it now let's go
我们将回到现在开始
back to the score and simply return at
回到分数，然后返回
42 now when I run the code it produced
42现在，当我运行它产生的代码时
42 but how has still is smart a normal
42但是怎么还聪明是正常的
order it says I don't have to evaluate
命令说我不必评估
ad after all because you're never using
毕竟是因为您从未使用过广告
the result of ad that's only possible
仅可能的广告结果
when functions are pure I'll talk about
当函数是纯函数时，我将讨论
that in a minute so because of that ad
一分钟之内
is never evaluated in this example let's
在此示例中从未评估过
prove it so let's go back here and run
证明一下，让我们回到这里运行
the Haskell GHz I Rapala gain let's go
Haskell GHz I Rapala增益开始吧
ahead and say in this case put a
提前说在这种情况下
breakpoint on line number one character
第一行字符上的断点
16 but called main this time and notice
16，但这次称为主通知
it never stepped into the function and
它从未涉足功能，
that's because hostile says there is no
那是因为敌意说没有
reason to evaluate that method add a
评估该方法的理由
function and because you're never using
功能，因为您从未使用过
the result of it
结果
that's efficiency is entered efficiency
效率就是效率
is
是
avoiding work that shouldn't be done in
避免不应做的工作
the first place you don't want to be
你不想成为的第一名
fast you want to be efficient when
快要高效时
you're efficient you're automatically
你有效率，你会自动
going to have better performance because
会有更好的表现，因为
you're not doing unnecessary work so how
您没有做不必要的工作，如何
is this even possible how would a skill
这甚至可能如何
do this that's because we have what are
这样做是因为我们拥有
called pure functions so what are really
叫做纯函数，所以真正的是
pure functions we are functions give
我们提供的纯函数
exactly the same result as long as the
只要结果完全相同
input is exactly the same every single
每个输入都完全相同
time pure functions will never give us a
时间纯函数永远不会给我们一个
different result for the given subset of
给定子集的不同结果
input we are functions don't have any
输入我们是函数没有任何
side effects so when you run the
副作用，所以当您运行
function you wouldn't know if they ran
您不知道它们是否运行的功能
or not anyway matter you wouldn't know
还是无论如何你都不知道
how what their effect was because they
他们的效果如何，因为他们
have no side effects so they take an
没有副作用，所以他们服用了
input they give an output if you don't
输入，如果没有，它们会提供输出
use the output it doesn't matter it's as
使用输出没关系，因为
if they were never actually run so what
如果他们从未真正运行过
are benefits of pure functions the first
首先是纯函数的好处
benefit is their idempotent you can call
好处是他们可以等幂
them any number of times for example you
他们很多次，例如你
call your bank and say what's my balance
打电话给你的银行，说我的余额是多少
and then immediately what's your balance
然后马上你的余额是多少
assuming it didn't really deposit any
假设它没有真正存放任何东西
money I would draw the balance will be
我会提取余额的钱将是
the same in this particular case usually
通常在这种情况下是一样的
that's not an idempotent operation
那不是幂等的运算
because the money in the bank keeps
因为银行里的钱不断
changing in a lot of cases keeps
在很多情况下不断变化
decreasing frustratingly but the point
令人沮丧地下降，但是重点
really is it keeps changing so
真的是在不断变化，所以
idempotency is when you can do the same
幂等是您可以做的相同的事情
work repeatedly and gives the same
反复工作并给出相同的结果
result like the add function
结果类似于添加功能
preferentially transparent you can call
可以透明地打电话给你
a function and you can replace the
功能，您可以替换
function or expression with its value so
函数或表达式及其值
for example in this eggs in this
例如在这个鸡蛋在这个
particular case has to put I have
特殊情况下我必须
decided to replace this add 1/3 with the
决定用替换此加法1/3
value of 4 if it wanted to it could do
如果它想做的话，值为4
this and that's referential transparency
这就是参考透明
in fact Java compiler does that but it
实际上Java编译器可以做到
knows that the functions are evaluations
知道功能是评估
expressions are pure it's easy to
表达式很纯净，很容易
memorize the result memorization is
记住结果记住
storing them so you can put them into a
存储它们，以便您可以将它们放入
cache and say the next time you call
缓存并在下次致电时说
this function I won't evaluate it I'll
这个功能我不会评估，我会
just give you this result back this is
只是给你这个结果，这是
used in what are called as dynamic
用于所谓的动态
programming problems an algorithmic
算法编程问题
approach where we use excess amount of
我们使用过量的方法
recursion but we save
递归，但我们保存
performance by memorizing code is easier
记忆代码可提高性能
to test as long as the input is the same
只要输入相同就进行测试
output is the same don't have any
输出是一样的没有任何
external dependencies awesome
外部依赖很棒
that's the dreamland for really having
那是真正拥有的理想国
ability to test it very easily and
可以很容易地测试它的能力
finally of course it's easier to
最后当然更容易
paralyze the code as well you can throw
也可以使代码麻痹
concurrency into a pure function because
并发成为纯函数，因为
it has no side effects it's not going to
它没有副作用，不会
run into any race conditions and mess
遇到任何比赛条件和混乱
with some shared global mutable state
具有一些共享的全局可变状态
and it's not gonna be affected by state
而且不会受到国家的影响
outside as well but for our purpose the
以及外部，但出于我们的目的
most interesting part here is it can be
这里最有趣的部分是
lazy so it can take it easy and wait
懒惰，这样可以轻松并等待
until it doesn't have to execute it or
直到不必执行它为止
until the last responsible moment
直到最后一个负责任的时刻
laziness is the real charm in this case
在这种情况下，懒惰才是真正的魅力
and what you just saw here was Haskell
你在这里看到的是Haskell
being lazy about implementing the add
懒于实现添加
functions of evaluation so it postponed
评估功能，因此推迟了
it long enough that it didn't have to do
足够长的时间，它不必做
it at all other languages that use
所有其他使用的语言
applicative order eagerly evaluate those
应用顺序急切地评估那些
things but like I said not like law
事情，但就像我说的不喜欢法律
language that weird equal haskell faults
怪异的Haskell错误的语言
on what I call a save the false it
在我所说的保存错误上
assumes all the functions are pure
假设所有功能都是纯函数
unless otherwise stated like we're just
除非另有说明，就像我们只是
like Java Scala and so on rely on you
像Java Scala等依赖于您
know fearing that functions are mutable
知道担心功能易变
unless otherwise stated so let's talk
除非另有说明，否则让我们谈谈
about Scala just for a little bit let's
关于Scala只是让我们
go to Scala real coin I'm going to
去我要去的Scala真实硬币
create a function right here called and
在这里创建一个函数，称为和
compute this takes a value int and it's
计算这需要一个值int并且它是
going to return let's say n times 2 well
打算返回n乘以2
I'm gonna go ahead and say Val X equal
我要说Val X等于
to 4 if X is greater than 5 and compute
如果X大于5则为4，然后计算
a for let's say is greater than 10 I
假设大于10我
want to go ahead an output print 1 let's
想要进行输出打印1让我们
say result 1 otherwise I'm going to
说结果1否则我要去
print out let's say a result 2 when I
打印出来，当我说结果2
run this code the question really to ask
运行这段代码真正要问的问题
us is color gonna run the compute method
我们有颜色会运行计算方法
we all know the answer foreign compute
我们都知道答案国外计算
will not run Y so that's called
不会运行Y，所以称为
short-circuiting hey great shot securing
短路，嘿，好球
is another example of laziness
是懒惰的另一个例子
it doesn't evaluate compute unless this
除非这不评估计算
one turned out to be true after all
毕竟是真的
so we know that conditionals have shots
所以我们知道有条件的人会出手
of queuing and laziness in place so if I
排队和懒惰的地方，如果我
go back here and say called right here
回到这里说在这里叫
you will notice that it was actually
您会注意到它实际上是
never called that's awesome but what if
从来没有说过很棒，但是如果
we take this out of here and call it him
我们把它从这里拿出来叫他
and we say over here valid temp is equal
我们说这里的有效温度等于
to compute sadly though this time how
可悲的是，尽管这次如何
what were when you run this Scala called
当您运行此Scala时，是什么意思
the compute method should it have called
计算方法应该已经调用
no of course not we're not using the
不，当然不是，我们不使用
result of compute but Scala evaluated
计算结果，但Scala评估了
compute eagerly why did it really do it
渴望计算为什么它真的做到了
the reason is Scala is worried that
原因是Scala担心
compute may have a side effect but wait
计算可能会有副作用，但请等待
a minute
一分钟
it had a side effect a minute ago when
一分钟前有副作用
we called it with compute right here so
我们在这里用计算来称呼它，所以
why did it not call it here but why does
为什么不在这里称呼它，为什么呢
it call it now the answer is very simple
现在说出来，答案很简单
language spec the language
语言规范语言
specifications rule language
规格规则语言
specifications say even if a function
规格说即使功能
were to have a side effect we will make
会有副作用，我们将使
we may not call them if those are in a
如果这些内容位于
short-circuit situation so language spec
短路情况，因此语言规范
language say is there you know times we
语言说，你知道吗？
will call methods if they have side
如果有方法会调用方法
effect here are times when we may not
在这里的影响有时是我们可能不会
even call it even if it has side effect
即使有副作用也可以称呼它
so it really boils down to language
所以真的可以归结为语言
specifications and in Scala chose to
规格，并在Scala中选择
call methods unless you are using in a
调用方法，除非您在
short circuited situation are you
短路情况是你吗
predominantly tell Scala it's okay by
主要告诉Scala没关系，
marking it as lazy by saying lazy you
通过说你懒将其标记为懒
are saying don't bother running this if
说不要打扰如果
you really don't need it as you can see
如您所见，您真的不需要它
in this example if I change it to a one
在这个例子中，如果我将其更改为一个
you will notice that it did call it but
您会注意到它确实调用了它，但是
if I put a five here it doesn't call it
如果我在这里放一个五，就不会这样
that's being lazy as we can see really
就像我们看到的那样，这很懒
beautiful as ended so you
美丽如初，所以你
have these tweaks and languages which
有这些调整和语言
you can use to control whether the
您可以用来控制是否
language is gonna exercise something or
语言会锻炼某些东西或
it's not going to exercise something
它不会运动
very powerful as you can see but what's
如您所见，功能非常强大，但是
really special about Java though well
关于Java真的很特别
Java has been predominantly a imperative
Java已成为当务之急
style an object-oriented style of
风格化
programming language so this has been
编程语言，所以这一直是
our experience in the past so when it
我们过去的经验，所以当它
comes to Java 7 and earlier we did
来到Java 7之前，我们做了
imperative plus object-oriented and
势在必行加上面向对象和
that's been the real mode of programming
那是编程的真实模式
in Java itself but starting with Java 8
Java本身，但从Java 8开始
what we can do is sure you can program
我们能做的是确保您可以编程
and later let's say Sheree can program
然后让我们说Sheree可以编程
an interactive style if you want to but
互动风格，如果您想
you can also do functional +
您也可以执行功能+
object-oriented with the hope that we
面向对象，希望我们
will do predominantly a functional
将主要做功能
rather than object rather than
而不是对象而不是
imperative rather so the real culprit
当务之急是真正的罪魁祸首
here is not object-oriented the real
这里不是面向对象的真实
culprit here is the imperative style of
罪魁祸首是命令式
programming by replacing the imperative
通过替换命令来编程
with functional we could still use
具有功能，我们仍然可以使用
infrared if you wanted to but we have
红外，如果你想，但我们有
the ability to replace at ports we can
在我们可以更换港口的能力
get some really good benefits and the
得到一些非常好的好处，
benefit as you can see in this case is
您在这种情况下看到的好处是
that charming feature of how we could do
我们该如何做的迷人特征
this in the function composition style
在函数组成风格上
but before we talk about this though
但是在我们谈论这个之前
let's talk about one benefit and how we
让我们谈谈一种好处，以及我们如何
can achieve that benefit so the real
可以实现这一利益，所以真正的
charm here in Java 8 is that Java 8
Java 8的魅力在于Java 8
actually does something a lot more than
实际上做的事情远不止于此
providing just a functional style of
提供只是一种函数式风格
programming Java did not walk away
编程Java并没有走开
saying here are lambdas good luck what
说这是lambdas，祝你好运
was right in the Java 8 book I don't
在我不了解的Java 8书中是正确的
something in the book which really
书中的某些内容
surprised me that even I wrote it but my
令我惊讶的是，即使我写了它，但我的
statement was that lambdas of the
声明是
gateway drug but streams are the real
门户毒品，但流才是真正的
addiction so the point really is that
瘾，所以重点是
the lambdas really draw you in
Lambda真的吸引了您
but the streams are the ones that are
但是流是
going to keep you and because if you
要留住你，因为如果你
don't have performance you're gonna
没有表现，你会
leave as soon as you come in but how do
一进来就离开，但是怎么办
streams give us performance let's talk
流让我们表现出色
about
关于
real quick let's get back to this
真快，让我们回到这个
example real fast and understand a one
快速真实的例子，并理解一个
key difference notice that an exam in
关键差异请注意
this example we have stream a stream is
这个例子我们有一个流
very different from a list let's talk
跟清单有很大的不同，让我们来谈谈
about these two for a minute put the
关于这两个一分钟，把
word list down for a second and also for
单词列表下来一秒钟，也
the word stream list is concrete on the
单词流列表是具体的
other hand stream is an abstraction yeah
另一手是抽象的耶
what does that really mean
那个的真实意义是什么
list is a container well this is a
清单是一个容器，这是一个
series of functions that still doesn't
一系列仍然没有的功能
ring the bell think of the word bucket I
敲钟想起我这个词桶
can have a bucket with a pile of water
可以有一个桶和一堆水
the bucket contains water in it I can
桶里装着水，我可以
store the water in a bucket I can come
把水放在桶里我可以来
back and use the water stored in the
返回并使用储存在
bucket list is a container we store
桶列表是我们存储的容器
stuff into it a stream on the other hand
另一方面塞入其中
is a pipe it liquid flows through it
是液体流过的管道
data flows through this pipe it's not
数据流经此管道不是
for storing things it's for transforming
用于存储东西，用于转换
and moving things a list is a container
将清单移动到容器中
like a bucket a stream is a series of
像水桶一样，溪流是一系列的
pipeline of functions to transform the
转换功能的管道
data along the way so in that regard
在这方面的数据
what is that what does it really mean to
这到底是什么意思
us what it means to us is a streams a
我们对我们意味着什么
series of transformations to understand
一系列了解的转变
this a little bit better let's go back
好一点，让我们回去
to another example we saw earlier and
另一个我们之前看到的例子
then we will relate back to this real
那么我们将回到这个真实的
quick let's bring back our sample dot RB
快速让我们带回我们的样本点RB
code right here and take a look at the
代码在这里，看看
Ruby code one more time if you look at
如果您查看Ruby代码，请再读一遍
this example watch carefully the
这个例子要仔细观察
execution path this Court took it
法院采取的执行路径
executed the is greater than function on
执行大于功能
every single value so what did Ruby do
每个值，那么Ruby做了什么
apply the first function on the entire
将第一个功能应用于整个
collection then it said apply the second
收藏然后说第二
function on the result collection so in
在结果集合上起作用
other words that's eager
渴望的其他话
keep that in mind we'll see how Java
记住这一点，我们将了解Java
does things very differently in the case
在这种情况下事情有很大不同
of Java Java is assuming that the lambda
Java的假设是lambda
expressions are pure this is one big
表情很纯正这是一大
difference between Haskell and Java has
Haskell和Java之间的区别是
got a bit boring in my opinion Haskell
我认为Haskell有点无聊
will come back and beat you down and say
会回来打败你并说
you will not mutate you will not have
你不会变异，你不会
side effects
副作用
Haskell will emphasize and verify and
Haskell将强调并验证和
confirm and follow you home sit next to
确认并跟随您回家坐在旁边
you stare at you and say it better be
你盯着你说最好
pure Java is a lot better in my opinion
我认为纯Java更好
for that reason because Java assumes
因此，因为Java假设
that lambdas are pure what happens when
Lambda是纯净的
a language assumes things when you and
当您和
Java disagree you know who wins so this
Java不同意你知道谁赢了，所以这
is one of the reasons why if you
是为什么如果你的原因之一
programmed in Haskell you'll go home on
在Haskell中编程，您将继续
time and your kids ask you how does that
时间，你的孩子问你怎么做
work mom and you're gonna say it was
工作妈妈，你会说这是
pouring everything I wrote word there's
倒所有我写的单词
no fun on the other hand you already
另一方面，你已经没有乐趣了
code in Java and maybe you forgot that
Java代码，也许您忘记了
these lambdas are pure you go home late
这些lambda很纯粹，你迟到了
after a very tiring day at work and you
在工作很累的一天之后，您
go home and the kids ask you how was
回家，孩子们问你过得怎么样
work how was the day and you say let me
工作一天过得怎么样，你说让我
tell you all about it we had a monster
告诉你一切，我们有一个怪物
we had to tackle and other stories to
我们不得不解决其他故事
tell that's one of the reasons why I
告诉我，这就是为什么我的原因之一
love these kinds of languages okay I'm a
喜欢这些语言，好吧，我是
little bit being kiddush here but the
这里有点开玩笑，但
point really though is don't forget Java
重点虽然是不要忘记Java
may not really warn you may not give you
可能不会真正警告您，可能不会给您
a error if you make mutations in lambdas
如果您在lambda中进行了变异，则会出现错误
because Java assumes lambdas are pure
因为Java假设lambda是纯的
the purity gives us laziness we talked
纯洁使我们说话变得懒惰
about so streams are inherently lazy so
左右流本质上是懒惰的
what is the benefit of that approach
这种方法的好处是什么
let's talk about this now as different
让我们现在谈论这个与众不同
in Java versus language like Ruby so in
Java与Ruby之类的语言
the case of Java the a collection of
Java的情况下
functions are applied on each element as
函数作为每个元素应用
as necessary so in
根据需要
of a function being up being a flight so
的功能是飞行
being applied applied upon each on the
被应用到每个
entire collection so let's revisit this
整个收藏，所以让我们重新回顾一下
one more time in the case of Ruby a
如果是Ruby，则再重复一次
function was applied on the entire
功能被整体应用
collection not so in Java a collection
集合不是Java中的集合
of functions are applied on each element
的功能应用于每个元素
as necessary so what Java does is it
必要时Java会做什么
takes these functions these are called
采取这些功能，这些被称为
intermediate operations so intermediate
中间操作如此中间
operations and these of course are
操作，这些当然是
called
叫
our terminal operations so in the case
我们的终端操作，因此
of Java
Java的
it'll take all the intermediate
它会花所有的中间
operations and what does do are fused
操作和功能融合在一起
together so it is going to take all
在一起，所以它将占据所有
these intermediate operations and it's
这些中间操作，
going to fuse them together into one
将它们融合在一起
collection of functions it dem applies
它所应用的功能的集合
the collection of functions on each
每个功能的集合
element but only as necessary so to
元素，但仅在必要时
understand this a little bit better
更好地理解这一点
let's take a look at a slightly
让我们来看看
different example here and work with it
在这里使用不同的示例并使用它
so rather than asking for all the people
因此，而不是要求所有人
who are younger than 18 and their name
18岁以下的年轻人及其名字
in uppercase let's say we want only the
用大写字母来说，我们只想要
first one so we'll go back here and we
第一个，所以我们回到这里，我们
will simply say dart find first and what
只会说dart首先找到什么
if we don't have a value what are we
如果我们没有价值，那我们是什么
gonna do would say our elves will say no
会说我们的精灵会说不
one found so when I run this little code
一个发现，所以当我运行这个小代码
now you can see that it produced Jack as
现在您可以看到它产生了Jack
the result of course in this case we can
在这种情况下，我们当然可以得到结果
go back and remove this operation right
返回并正确删除此操作
here
这里
that's the imperative style and we will
这是当务之急的风格，我们将
simply use the function of style code
只需使用样式代码的功能
right here an except Jack well it found
就在这里，除了杰克，
the first value in this collection in
此集合中的第一个值
this output let's go back and remove the
此输出让我们返回并删除
commented out code and run this how does
注释掉代码并运行此方法
this go really work well imagine you are
这个去真的很好，想象你是
at work and on
在工作中
the 15 the boss calls you and says I can
老板给你打电话说15
produce for you
为你生产
you got a project you're gonna start on
你有一个项目要开始
it and it's due on April the 15th do you
它应该在4月15日到期
come out of the boss's office on January
一月份从老板办公室出来
the 15th and start on it right away of
15号，马上就开始
course not
当然不是
you will start on it promptly on April
您将在四月立即开始
the 14th isn't it because it's due on
第十四不是吗，因为它应该在
that's called efficiency well the point
那就是所谓的效率点
really is we don't do things until those
真的是我们不做那些事
become relevant and imminent in fact if
变得相关和迫在眉睫
you know you're gonna quit on March 1st
你知道你要在3月1日辞职
why would you even start on this any any
你为什么还要开始这个
sooner than that the point really is we
早于这一点，真正的是我们
have by not doing things you don't have
通过不做你没有的事情而拥有
to do right now you are able to focus on
现在就可以专注于
things that have to be done right now
现在必须要做的事情
and if things are not relevant
如果事情不相关
eventually you don't have to do it and
最终，您不必这样做，
that's called efficiency so I'll find
这就是所谓的效率，我会发现
somebody was really really busy and give
有人真的很忙，付出
them work and they get done but how
他们工作，他们就完成了，但是如何
because they prioritize and they don't
因为他们优先考虑而他们没有
waste time doing things that are
浪费时间做事情
unnecessary that's exactly the point is
没必要，这才是重点
that you want to be efficient in what
您想要在什么方面高效
you do not just simply faster so both
您不仅会更快，所以两者
wise and in programming laziness is the
明智的是，在编程中，懒惰是
ultimate sophistication as we can see
如我们所见，终极成熟
here let's prove that right now so when
现在让我们证明一下
you run the code you see you got Jack
您运行代码，看到杰克
but let's go to the person class real
但让我们去真正的人课堂
quick in the person class I remember we
我记得我们在人际班上快
asked for the age first and then the
先问年龄，然后问
name so let's go to the age function and
名称，让我们转到年龄函数，然后
we will output right here get age called
我们将在这里输出，将年龄称为
for and in this case we'll output the
为此，在这种情况下，我们将输出
name of the person likewise we'll go
这个人的名字我们也要去
ahead and say in this case then name
向前说在这种情况下，然后说出名字
itself will say get name called for so
自己会说得到这样的名字
this will be get name for then of course
当然，这将是名字
we'll print out the neat and details of
我们将打印出整齐的细节
that but if this were eager remember
那但如果这很切记
what happened in language like Ruby
Ruby这样的语言发生了什么
it was eager and executed the first
渴望并执行了第一个
method for every single thing if John
约翰每件事的方法
was eager it will ask for the age of
渴望能问到年龄
every single person including this jack
每个人，包括这个杰克
and this Jill however in this particular
而这个吉尔在这个特殊的
case because jack is the result we
案例，因为杰克是我们的结果
looking for it we'll never have to touch
寻找它，我们将永远不必碰
this tack and this joke may not be such
这样的笑话和这个笑话可能不是这样
a big deal in this case but what if this
在这种情况下很重要，但是如果这
were a million elements a lot of
是一百万个元素
elements after this one we don't want to
在此之后的元素我们不想
evaluate them once we find a result so
找到结果后对它们进行评估，以便
in this case the get age is going to be
在这种情况下，年龄将是
called on on what it will be called on
调用了将要调用的内容
Sarah Sarah Bob para Paul and Jack
莎拉（Sarah）
however there's one big difference
但是有一个很大的不同
though it's not going to call the get a
尽管它不会调用get
john all the elements first again if you
约翰，如果你再把所有要素都放在首位
go back to this example and run this
回到这个例子并运行
notice that evaluated YZ g t-54 all
请注意，评估后的YZ g t-54全部
elements only after that it started
元素才开始
evaluating the double function not so in
评估double函数不是这样
Java it evaluate the group of these
Java评估这些组
functions as necessary on one element at
根据需要在一个元素上起作用
a time so I run this code notice it
一段时间，所以我运行此代码，请注意
called get age on Sarah Sarah Bob Paula
叫萨拉（Sarah）变老Sarab Bob Paula
Paul Jack but then it calls get name on
保罗·杰克（Paul Jack），但随后电话打响
Jack but it never touched the second
杰克，但从未触及第二
Jack and B and the Jill hmm doesn't
杰克和B和吉尔（Jill）嗯
quite illustrate what I wanted to show
很好地说明了我想展示的内容
here yet isn't it let's try a little
这里不是吗，让我们尝试一下
different example let's say I want the
举例来说，我想要
first person who was older than 20 but
20岁以上但第一人称
it was also a female older than 20 well
也是一位年龄超过20岁的女性
that's Sarah but also a female that's
那是莎拉，也是一位女性
Sarah - let's make it all in the man 30
莎拉-让我们一起成为男人30
that'll be this Paula great so let's
那将是宝拉很棒，所以让我们
evaluate that
评估
so get H is greater than 30 and then I
所以得到H大于30然后我
want to say that filter in this case of
想说在这种情况下的过滤器
course and we want to say given a person
当然，我们想说给一个人
will say person dark get gender and in
会说人黑暗得到性别
this case of course is equal to gender
这种情况当然等于性别
dot female when I run this little code
当我运行这个小代码时，点女性
let's go ahead and comment these out for
让我们继续进行评论
just a second we'll come back to this
请稍等一下
and we will go ahead and put the print
我们将继续进行打印
children the gender as well so we can
也让孩子们有性别，所以我们可以
look at it to here so here is the Jo get
看着它到这里，所以这里是乔得到
gender so we'll say get gender call for
性别，所以我们说让性别呼吁
so
所以
and then of course the name let's go
然后当然要走了
ahead and run this real example that's
继续并运行这个真实的例子是
Paula if this were eager you were asked
宝拉（Paula）是否急于要求您
for age of everyone gender for everyone
每个人的年龄
or than 30 name of everyone older than
或30岁以上所有人的名字
30 and female convert all the names only
30和女性仅转换所有名称
to throw away most of the work but not
丢掉大部分工作，但没有
so in this example if I go back in
所以在这个例子中，如果我回到
uncomment these print statements though
取消注释这些打印语句
what you notice right here is that when
您在这里注意到的是
we Wonder's look at the sequence of the
我们想知道的顺序
output it called get a John Sarah it
输出它叫得到约翰·萨拉
called get 8 on the second Sarah it
在第二个Sarah叫get 8
called on Bob and Paula then gender and
拜访鲍勃和宝拉，然后性别
Paula name are para and done if I were
宝拉的名字是帕拉，如果我是
to flip this over asking for all the
把这个翻过来，要求所有
females first and then the age then you
首先是女性，然后是年龄
notice it asks for gender on Sarah and
注意它要求在Sarah和
age on Sarah right away gender innate on
萨拉（Sarah）的年龄马上就性别先天
the second Sarah right away gender
第二个莎拉马上就性别
gender on Bob and Paula age on Paula and
Bob和Paula的性别，Paula和
Mayman Paula look at only the first four
Mayman Paula只看前四个
lines for me notice get gender get age
对我而言，注意事项变性别变年龄
then again get gender and get age then
然后再次获得性别并获得年龄
again get gender in other words unlike
换句话说，再次获得性别
Ruby where all of the methods of one
Ruby其中所有方法之一
line were executed eagerly this is being
线被急切地执行，这是
absolutely lazy it evaluates a little
绝对懒惰，它有点评估
bit of the first function and the second
第一个功能和第二个功能的位
and goes as long as it can go in other
只要它可以进入其他地方
words it fuses these functions
文字融合了这些功能
collection of function apply on one
功能集合适用于一个
element Sarah and if necessary on the
元素莎拉，如果需要的话
second and the third but the minute it
第二和第三但一分钟
finds the answer it no longer applies it
找到答案不再适用
in fact let's go to the next level to
实际上，让我们进入下一个层次
see how laziness really plays a role in
看看懒惰如何真正在
here if we were to go back to this
如果我们要回到这里
example and let's remove the print line
例子，让我们删除打印行
for a second and in this case I'm going
一秒钟，在这种情况下，我要去
to go ahead and say done right here when
继续说在这里什么时候完成
I execute the code you can see all that
我执行代码，您可以看到所有
output and they're done however if I
输出，但是如果我完成了
were to go back and comment out just the
会回去只评论
last two lines over here then we're not
最后两行，那么我们不是
calling the terminal method we have this
调用终端方法，我们有这个
collection of this terminal functions
该终端功能的集合
fused together but we never call the
融合在一起，但我们从不称之为
terminal method it's a terminal method
终端方法这是一种终端方法
that triggers the evaluation as you can
可以触发评估
see in here the result is simply done it
看到这里的结果就完成了
doesn't really execute all the
并没有真正执行所有
intermediate functions
中间功能
it's absolutely lazy I've been working
我一直在偷懒
on a project where we are dealing with
在我们正在处理的项目中
literally millions and millions of
数以百万计的
pieces of data we've been running it
我们一直在运行的数据
through the functional pipeline through
通过功能管道
lambdas in fact a lot of lambdas and
lambdas实际上很多lambdas和
we're not seeing any performance
我们没有看到任何表现
degradation due to lambdas or due to
由于lambda或由于
pipeline in fact there's a benefit we
管道实际上是有好处的
get right off the bat not only can we
马上行动，我们不仅可以
have efficiency through lace evaluation
通过花边评估提高效率
we can also paralyze the scored also
我们也可以使得分麻痹
more easily to get there as a faster if
更容易到达那里，如果
we have a lot of data to process so in
我们有很多数据需要处理
other words the function of style of
换句话说，风格的功能
programming is very charming the
编程很迷人
function pipelining
功能流水线
is beautiful it removes the accidental
很漂亮，它消除了意外
complexity from the code compared to a
代码的复杂度与
imperative style code a function of
命令式代码的功能
style code is a single pass through the
样式代码是一次通过
code begins to read like the problem
代码开始像问题一样读
statement we can relate to what the code
声明我们可以关联什么代码
is doing and we can quickly understand
正在做，我们可以快速了解
it it removes that accidental complexity
它消除了意外的复杂性
and makes the code easier to understand
使代码更容易理解
the code is cookies every single line of
代码是Cookie的每一行
code that's one thing only this line
仅此行的代码
checks if a person is a female or male
检查一个人是女性还是男性
this checks if the a age is greater than
这会检查年龄是否大于
30 this gets the name this transforms
30这得到转换的名称
the name to uppercase compare this to
大写的名字比较
the previous code we wrote where a line
我们之前编写的代码在一行
was doing multiple things lack of
在做很多事情缺乏
cohesion this one is easier to remove
凝聚力这更容易消除
some pieces or to add some pieces it's
一些碎片或添加一些碎片
cohesive a cohesive code is easier to
内聚的内聚的代码更容易
modify the code removes the impedance
修改代码以消除阻抗
mismatch of trying to figure out and
试图弄清楚和不匹配
extract the details of business logic
提取业务逻辑的细节
from the code the code becomes the
从代码中，代码变成
business logic the code becomes easier
商业逻辑，代码变得更容易
to
至
understand and see what it's doing but
了解并看到它在做什么，但是
of course we cannot claim all this
当然我们不能声称所有这一切
beauty is great but we can't give
美丽是伟大的，但我们不能放弃
performance so to me what really grabbed
性能对我来说真的很抢手
my attention in Java was not the fact
我对Java的关注不是事实
that Java has lambda expressions have
Java有lambda表达式
you slammed as in other languages Ruby
你猛烈抨击其他语言Ruby
groovy Python to name a few and Scala of
时髦的Python等等
course in closure and so on however
当然是关闭，依此类推
these all these beautiful function
所有这些漂亮的功能
pipelining and expressive code these
这些的流水线和表达代码
things we can only frame and celebrate
我们只能构架和庆祝的事情
but can't really use on big projects and
但不能真正在大型项目中使用
big data projects if the language does
如果语言支持，则可以进行大数据项目
not support lazy evaluation so the fact
不支持懒惰的评估，所以事实
that Java supports laziness is one of
Java支持懒惰是其中之一
the most charming features streams are
最迷人的功能流是
really powerful but there are
真的很强大，但是有
limitations to stream as well in Java
Java中流式传输的限制
Java streams unfortunately don't handle
不幸的是，Java流无法处理
exceptions really well and if you really
例外真的很好，如果真的
want to do powerful streaming there are
想做强大的流媒体
other things you can do for example the
您可以做的其他事情，例如
reactive programming model observables
反应式编程模型可观察
and flow those ideas are not very
并流动那些想法不是很
different from streams just the streams
与溪流不同的只是溪流
implemented in Java has a few
用Java实现的有一些
limitations we do use streams quite
限制我们确实使用流
extensively when we don't really have to
当我们不需要的时候
worry about those limitations depends on
担心这些限制取决于
the case but just like I said languages
的情况，但就像我说的语言
are created different one of the reasons
被创造出不同的原因之一
I got really excited about Java was not
我为Java感到非常兴奋
the fact that Java has lambdas what
Java有lambdas的事实
really got me who don't Java was that
真正让我懂Java的人是
streams are lazy in fact it's the
流很懒，实际上是
laziness that drew me into Java 8 and
懒惰吸引了我进入Java 8和
I've been singing its praise ever since
从那以后我一直在赞美它
if Java had not implemented laziness
如果Java没有实现懒惰
into streams API we wouldn't be talking
到流API，我们不会谈论
about and getting excited about Java 8
关于Java 8并感到兴奋
and so I'll conclude by saying laziness
所以我最后会说懒惰
is the ultimate sophistication both in
两者的终极复杂性
programming and in life hope that was
编程和生活中的希望是
useful thank you
有用的谢谢
you
您